Register of the Liberian Subject Collection, 1866-2001
Hoover Institution Archives
Liberian Subject Collection,
1866-2001
XX784
12 manuscript boxes, 1 oversize box, 2 videotape cassettes (5.7 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Electronic bulletins, pamphlets, reports, serial issues, and other printed matter, relating to political, social and economic conditions in Liberia, and to the coups of 1980 and 1990.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Materials were acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
Liberia--History--Coup d'etat, 1980.; Liberia.; Africa.; Video tapes.
Series Description
- SUBJECT FILE, 1956-1995. (Boxes 1-2.)
  Bulletins, communiques, correspondence, leaflets, magazines, pamphlets, printed matter, serial issues, statements and statutes relating to the economic, political and social conditions in Liberia
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1980-1990. (Tape cabinet)
  Two videocassette tapes
Container List
See card catalog for increments that may have been received after January 1995
- SUBJECT FILE, 1956-1995
  - General (Box 1)
    - General
    - Bong Crier
    - Harvest, The
    - New Vision
    - Palm
    - People, The
    - Sunday People, The
    - X-RAY
  - Agriculture
  - Economics
    - General
    - Economic Community of West African States. Includes letter from Jimmy Carter
    - Investment
  - Education
    - General
    - University of Liberia
  - Foreign relations
    - Nigeria
    - United States
  - Health
  - Human rights
  - Media
  - Opposition
    - General
    - Movement for Justice in Africa (MOJA)
  - Politics and government (Box 2)
    - General
    - Association for Constitutional Democracy in Liberia
    - Coup, 12 April 1980
    - Doe, President Dr. Samuel Kanyon
    - Free Democratic Party
    - Greene, Vice President James Edward
    - Interim Government of National Unity
    - Ministry of Labor
  - Women
- AUDIO-VISUAL FILE, 1980-1990
  - Videocassette tapes (Tape-cabinet Tape cabinet)
    - "Liberia: The Doe Era, 1980-1990": 1980 execution; 1985 November 12 invasion; 1990 June 13 interview with Charles Taylor, Samuel Doe, Bull, Cooper and Cohen; 1990 September 9 capture of Doe by Prince Johnson; and 1990 November 1 raw footage of Liberia
    - "Liberia: A Friend in Need," 1990 November and Samuel K. Doe's interrogation, 1990 September
- Incremental Materials (Box 3-13:)
  This addition to the collection has not yet been described. Please let the Hoover Institution Archives know if you would like to see this material described.